Shreya Lohakare

New York, New York +1 (201) 936 4377 slohakar@pratt.edu | LinkedIn

I am a multi-faceted designer with a solution-focused mindset. I specialize in creating well-crafted user-centric, inclusive products through collaborative methods with a Human-Centered approach.

Education

M.S. Information Experience Design

2024-Present | New York, New York

Pratt Institute,

Relevant Coursework: Product Design, Conversational Design, Information Architecture, Foundations of Information, Information Technology

Bachelor of Architecture

2018-2023 | Pune, India

Marathwada Mitramandal's College of Architecture,

Extracurricular: Technical head, Designed academic infographics, and print materials for school promotion.

Experience

Shrutika Raut Design Studio

August 2023 - May 2024 | Pune, India

Junior Architect

- Led architectural and interior design projects, applying user-centered design solutions, reducing client costs by 5%.
- Led cross-functional teams of site engineers, project managers, and designers to successfully deliver architecture and interior design projects giving user-centered design solutions.
- Developed and implemented user satisfaction survey in the company system for requirement-capturing enabling the design of more tailored and client-specific products.
- Redesigned the studio's website using Wix optimizing its information architecture and web design, leading to a 40% increase in online engagement.
- Developed presentations and infographics utilizing graphic design principles, prototyping, and 3D visualization tools(AutoCAD, SketchUp, Lumion), enhancing client understanding and resulting in an 80% conversion rate from potential clients to confirmed projects.
- Led the social media management, growing the studio's reach by 60% through cohesive visual design and strategic content planning, further driving client acquisition and engagement.

Samyak C2 Infra. Pvt. Ltd.

May 2022 - November 2022 | Pune, India

Architectural Intern

- Studied user needs by carrying out user research to make informed design decisions for commercial and campus projects, which reduced construction costs by 7%.
- Conducted market research for BIM management and quantification for SC2 construction standards and
 cost codes ensuring accuracy in design data, similar to managing large-scale information architecture
 systems in digital design. It was successfully implemented throughout the company leading to a
 streamlined working system.

KAAS Design Studio

March 2021 – September 2021 | Pune, India

Architectural Intern

- Created user journey maps and 3D prototypes using AutoCAD and SketchUp, iterating on designs to achieve the most suitable design.
- Coordinated with vendors and execution team, to ensure translation of design concepts on-site.
- Employed heuristic evaluation to refine designs, ensuring functionality and usability in interior projects

Skills

Design

Visual Design, Prototyping, UI Design, Graphic Design, Information Architecture, Print Design, Web Design, Storyboarding, Architectural Design, Creative Problem Solving, 3D Visualization, Layouting

Research and Tools

User Interviews, User Journey Maps, Tree Testing, Surveys, Competitive Audits, Heuristic Evaluation, Lab Studies, Information Architecture, and Prototyping.

Figma, Sketch, Google Analytics, Miro, Adobe Creative Suite, UserTesting, Optimal Workshop, Voiceflow,

G-Suite, MS Office, Autodesk AutoCAD, Autodesk Revit, Google Sketchup, Lumion, Microsoft Office Suite.